His defiance will never be silenced.
Truth & Treason is a history, drama, thriller film directed by Matt Whitaker.
When loyalty to country becomes loyalty to a lie, one
teen risks everything to expose the truth.
With the Gestapo closing in, he must decide what it
really means to be a good German.
Helmuth Hübener, played by Ewan Horrocks.
Erwin Mussener, played by Rupert Evans.
Karl-Heinz Schnibbe, played by Ferdinand McKay.
Rudi Wobbe, played by Daf Thomas.
Solomon Schwarz, played by Nye Occomore.
Emma Hübener, played by Joanna Christie.
Truth & Treason is a 2025 American drama film based on the true story of Helmuth Hübener, a
teenage resistance fighter who opposed the Nazi regime in Germany during WWII.
The film was previously titled Truth & Conviction.
The project is directed by Matt Whitaker, who also
wrote the film alongside Ethan Vincent.
It is produced by Russ Kendall, John Foss, and Matt
Whitaker, with Adam Thomas Anderegg and Micah W.
Merrill as executive producers.
The film was released in the United States on October 17, 2025.
The film explores themes of nonviolent resistance, based on true story,
anti-nazi resistance, historical drama, nsdap (nazi party).
The tone is intense and dark and emotional.